### Coordonnées

www.linkedin.com/in/federica-drobnitzky-2a695213b (LinkedIn)

Principales compétences

Public Relations

Strategy

New Business Development

### Languages

German (Native or Bilingual)
English (Full Professional)
French (Professional Working)
Dutch (Elementary)

# Federica Drobnitzky

Communications Consultant I Project Manager # ### # ## Integrated campaigning & brand strategy

Bruxelles

### Résumé

I am a communications consultant, project manager and strategic creative thinker. I see communication as a powerful tool to entertain, but more importantly to raise awareness, promote (social) change and create lasting impact.

In recent years I have worked both on the agency side and in the institutional sphere. My expertise lies in the management, steering and implementation of broad, integrated communication campaigns and event activities. In doing so, I have dealt with various topics: Work-life balance for working mothers, environment, migration and integration, access to information, (EU) investment, taxation, consumer rights and local development.

Besides campaigning, I also like to get involved strategically in new business activities. I have recently participated in various pitches for the European Commission and United Nations agencies and have been involved in identifying new business areas.

I am originally from Germany and hold a MA in Communication, Media and Creative Industries from Sciences Po Paris (Summa Cum Laude). Having worked and studied in London, Berlin, Paris and now Brussels, I have learned to quickly navigate and feel comfortable in international environments.

# Expérience

Scholz & Friends Consultant & Project Manager janvier 2018 - août 2021 (3 ans 8 mois)

Brussels, Belgium

European Office I Clients: DG COMM, DG ENV, DG JUST, DG TRADE, DG REGIO; UNESCO

- Strategic advisory for pan-European communication campaigns, event communication activities and smaller projects on behalf of EU and UN bodies
- 360° project management, from steering of strategy and creative teams to (paid/earned media) channel planning, playout and performance monitoring
- New business development and strategy

#### **WPP**

Project Manager juillet 2018 - décembre 2019 (1 an 6 mois) Brussels Area, Belgium

EU Team I Government & Public Sector Practice (GPSP)

- Project management and events organisation for WPP's GPSP EU Hub: Coordination of horizontal, internal consortium relations among WPP agencies; organisation of regular events fostering internal agency and external client relations and visibility
- New business management

#### **UNESCO**

Project Coordinator juillet 2017 - septembre 2017 (3 mois) Paris Area, France

Communication Sector I United Nations' International Programme for the Development of Communication (IPDC)

- 360° organisation of the 'IPDCTalks', UNESCO's main (TEDTalk-like) event on the International Day for Universal Access to Information, from event logistics to speaker guidance
- Development and implementation of a awareness campaign to drive visibility for and attendance in the IPDCTalks, including: (Social) media strategy development (trending topic on Twitter in 10 different countries on the day of the event); Multi-channel content & promotional material development and steering (social, website, media); Management of creative teams for production of various promotional materials (posters, flyers, roll-ups, graphics, GIFs, videos)
- Development of IPDCTalks student contest that engaged students from all over the world

Amnesty International Germany
Press Office Assistant
octobre 2015 - décembre 2015 (3 mois)
Page 2 of 4

Berlin Area, Germany

Press Office I Communication & Campaigns

- Handling and answering of (inter)national press inquiries
- Monitoring of Al's press resonance (German market), creation of press evaluations and drafting of press material
- Co-organisation of events such as press conferences (on the occasion of National Refugee Day, International Human Rights Day etc.), congresses and workshops

Edelman.ergo GmbH
Communications Intern & Assistant
mars 2015 - octobre 2015 (8 mois)
Berlin Area, Germany

Politics & Economy Department I Client: German Federal Ministry for Family Affairs

- Generating editorial content for the project 'Reconciliation of Family and Work' (Vereinbarkeit von Familie & Beruf), as well as its sub-programmes 'Local Alliances for Families' (Lokale Bündnisse für Familie) and 'Success Factor Family' (Erfolgsfaktor Familie)
- Development of weekly press evaluations in regards to above-mentioned initiatives and preparation of media resonance analyses
- Contribution to organisation of event 'Vereinbarkeitskonvent 2015' with Manuela Schwesig

Claudia Wünsch communication Communications Intern octobre 2012 - mars 2013 (6 mois) Berlin Area, Germany

Lifestyle, Art & Fashion Department I Clients: Hugo Boss, La Perla, Furla, Anthropologie etc.

- Community management on several client social media accounts
- Development and dissemination of press material
- Weekly press evaluation via clipping-presentations
- Co-organisation of showroom presentations at the German press days
- Establishment and maintenance of media database

Newspaper Publisher Neue Westfälische GmbH & Co. KG

### Freelance Journalist

juin 2008 - janvier 2009 (8 mois)

Gütersloh, Germany

- Drafting of news articles and reports (print edition)
- Taking photos to supplement articles

## Formation

Sciences Po

Master's degree, Communications, Media and Creative Industries · (2016 - 2018)

Freie Universität Berlin

Bachelor's degree, Media & Communications Studies / German Language & Literature  $\cdot$  (2011 - 2015)